Debadutta Sahoo

UI/UX Designer

- Charlotte, NC
- **1** 704-575-7238
- debaduttabehera45
 6@gmail.com

Skills →

- Visual Design
- Wireframing
- Prototyping
- User Flows
- Style Guide
- Web Design
- Mobile Design
- Responsive Design



- Sketch
- Invision
- Marvel
- Flinto
- Balsamiq
- Draw.io
- Photoshop

- Competitive analysis
- User stories
- Personas
- User flows
- Usability testing

- Scrum
- Agile
- Jira
- ▶ HP ALM
- Java and Selenium
- ▶ HTML, CSS, Java Script

✓—— Office Tools ——▶

- Microsoft Word
- Microsoft Excel
- Power Point

https://deedee135.github.io/Debadutta.Sahoo-portfolio/

Passionate UI/UX designer with 3+ years of experience in quality and business analysis. Skilled at creating visually attractive and thoughtful interfaces based on principles of design, and has strong visual design sense with knowledge of current web design trends and techniques, i.e. HTML/CSS. Demonstrate the ability to present and explain design decisions to team members and stakeholders.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance UI/UX Designer

April 2020 - Present

- Design UI from inception to final product and successfully launched brand new **MeetMonk** Inc website and other internal pages.
- Design mockups for websites layout and created final web assets.
- Work closely with the product owner to design pixel-perfect responsive designs.
- Create visual prototypes that demonstrated new concepts and features.

Business Analyst

TIAA-CREF, Charlotte, North carolina

April 2019 - Dec 2019

- Created UML diagrams, such as use cases, process flow diagrams, and data flow diagrams.
- Created/updated projects, user stories, and tracking progress and all relevant work in JIRA.
- Worked as a part of the team and communicated effectively with software developers, product managers, and other staff.

UAT Expert

LPL Financial, Fort Mill, South carolina

March 2018 - February 2019

- Developed and executed test plans to ensure the accurate development of more complex system changes from a business and functional perspective.
- Communicated with UAT Test Leads and IT Development to identify and track defects and defect fixes.

QA Analyst

Fusion Informatics, USA

February 2017 - February 2018

- Executed the test cases, identified defects, classified and raised defects, participated in defect triages.
- Demonstrated understanding of the concepts of unit testing, smoke testing, integration testing, system testing, and regression testing

EDUCATION

CareerFoundry 2019 - 2020

Certified UI Designer

QSpider 2017

Java and Selenium Certification

Frameboxx Animation, India 2010

SOA University, India 2005 -2009

Bachelor in Computer Science